RAMA JAKARIA

rama.jakaria@gmail.com | ramjak.github.io | https://id.linkedin.com/in/ramjak



Summary

Web developer with more than 4 years of experience in front-end and back-end development. Most of my experience dealing with start-up project which demands quick development and ever-changing requirement, so when I code I always try to balancing development speed and project maintainability.

Formal Education

1. <u>Gadjah Mada University</u> – Computer Science Aug 2012 – Aug 2018 Thesis: "Data Preprocessing for Facial Expression Recognition"

Skill

Front-End: Responsive Web, React, React Native, Javascript

Back-End: Laravel, PHP, MySQL, Python, MongoDB

Tools : Git, Jest

Language: Bahasa Indonesia (Native), English (TOEFL 560)

Experience

Pand.ai as Senior Front-End Developer

Sep 2019 - Mei 2021

- converted design into ReactJS Component using Typescript, StyledComponent, Redux-Saga
- created REST API specification based on design
- developed a real-time chat service using Socket.io, React, and Typescript
- performed security tests on a website and fixed the vulnerabilities found from the test
- tested and improved the performance of a ReactJS website

Freelance 2013 - Now

- managed contract and requirement
- communicated with the project owner and design the application based on the specification
- converted from PSD to HTML

- created a working web app
- deployed the project to the server

Here are projects that I built and techs that I used:

- Sentiment Analysis Dashboard, July 2018, using Python, MongoDB, and Angular
- Iwak.me (Delivery System), Feb 2018, using ReactJS, Redux, Google Maps API, Socket.io client, SCSS. HTML
- CoAnalis, November 2016, using Laravel, HTML, CSS, jQuery
- Smart Pollution Monitoring System, Mar 2015, using Laravel, Python, Leaflet.js
- Anava #9, Nov 2014, using Laravel, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Bootstrap, jQuery
- Blood Donor Management System, Oct 2013, using Laravel, HTML, CSS

Wideboard as Front-End Developer

Sep 2018 - Sep 2019

- planned and implemented the project architecture based on specification
- converted PDF design into ReactJS Component using Typescript, SCSS
- developed a real-time chat service using WebSocket, RxJS, and Redux
- developed a browser push notification system using service-worker
- established a workflow that fit the team

Wonderlabs as Mobile Web Developer

Mar 2018 – Aug 2018

- created a React Native app
- developed a communication system between hardware and phone using Bluetooth
- developed Over-The-Air hardware update system
- converted Android component into React Native component
- developed service to manage real-time communication between devices using RxJS
- add unit tests to minimize bugs in future development using Jest

Wonderlabs as ReactJS Developer

Dec 2016 - Feb 2018

- planned website development from the specification
- transformed static website into single page application using ReactJS, Redux, Javascript, HTML, SCSS
- add data visualization using D3.js
- add unit tests and integration tests to minimize bugs in future development with 80% coverage using Jest

Wonderlabs as PHP Developer

Aug 2016 - Nov 2016

- developed an application using Symfony, PHP, HTML, CSS, and MySQL
- developed and bug fixed a pass-down project using Laravel
- created an article recommendation client-SDK using vanilla Javascript

Kreasi Kode as Web Developer

April 2016 – Jun 2016

- developed features on an existing system built with Codelgniter, PHP, Oracle, HTML, and SCSS
- bug fixed the old features and performance issue

Skyshi Digital as Drupal Developer Intern

Jan 2015 – Feb 2015

- creating a working back-end with Drupal and PHP
- integrating the front-end team output, a static website, into a dynamic website
- add interactivity to the website with jQuery